<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Josh Lynn</title>
    <link>http://lynnjm7.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Josh Lynn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016 Josh Lynn</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 13:07:45 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://lynnjm7.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>http://lynnjm7.github.io/publication/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 13:07:45 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lynnjm7.github.io/publication/resume/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;education&#34;&gt;Education&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BS Computer Science, math minor. University of Nevada, Las Vegas, December 2012&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;skills&#34;&gt;Skills&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Programming Languages:&lt;/strong&gt; C, C++, C#, Java, Objective-C, Swift, Python, JavaScript, Go&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Graphics Libraries and Tools:&lt;/strong&gt; OpenGL, OpenGL ES, WebGL, GLSL, CUDA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Databases:&lt;/strong&gt; SQLite, MySQL, PostgreSQL, DynamoDB, MongoDB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Operating Systems:&lt;/strong&gt; macOS, Windows, Linux, iOS, Android&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Development Tools:&lt;/strong&gt; Git, Maven, Gradle, Make, Android Studio/IntelliJ, Xcode, Visual Studio, Vim&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Development Methodologies:&lt;/strong&gt; Scrum, Agile, TDD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;employment-history&#34;&gt;Employment History&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lead-software-engineer-apartments247-com-june-2015-present&#34;&gt;Lead Software Engineer, Apartments247.com, &lt;em&gt;June 2015 ~ Present&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the responsibilities discussed in the &lt;code&gt;Software Engineer&lt;/code&gt; position
below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managed a team of 8-12 engineers on various projects, including REST APIs,
iOS and Android apps, and internal tooling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supervised team of engineers and designers in creating a series of mobile apps
for residents of apartment communities. These apps were designed to be white
labeled for the branding of various communities. The apps were implemented
with Ionic and Apache Cordova.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Directly lead team in developing REST APIs on AWS infrastructure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;software-engineer-apartments247-com-december-2014-present&#34;&gt;Software Engineer, Apartments247.com, &lt;em&gt;December 2014 ~ Present&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lead engineer on constructing JSON REST APIs and a distributed, microservice
infrastructure on AWS. The services were built leveraging different AWS
services including, SQS, DynamoDB, Aurora, Lambda, EC2, S3, and API Gateway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Engineered and implemented an Internet Listing Service (ILS) for apartment
communities. The Aptcast ILS was implemented with Swift (with some use of
C and Objective-C for various components) and released for iPhone. Project
discontinued due to business decisions to focus on Resident apps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed and implemented the original microservice APIs in Go, Node, and Python
that were used for the Aptcast apps. These became the foundation for new
product development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;software-development-engineer-contract-galavantier-february-2014-july-2014&#34;&gt;Software Development Engineer (Contract), Galavantier, &lt;em&gt;February 2014 ~ July 2014&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technical lead on &lt;em&gt;Marko&amp;rsquo;s Guest List&lt;/em&gt; iOS app, implemented in Objective-C. The
app consumed a JSON REST API.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintained and extended existing Drupal REST APIs with PHP and MySQL.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented a custom Customer Service pipeline to aid service representatives
in responding to leads generated from the iOS app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;software-engineer-contract-lambda-td-software-inc-june-2013-december-2013&#34;&gt;Software Engineer (Contract), Lambda TD Software, Inc., &lt;em&gt;June 2013 ~ December 2013&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented features and bug fixes on the  &lt;em&gt;LFE Five Home Automation Platform&lt;/em&gt;. The platform
consisted of a REST API implemented in Java with Spring and PostgreSQL. The goal of the project
was to create a system that would provide a common interface for users to be able to interact
with multiple different home automation protocols. This was achieved by interacting with
various home automation protocol through their official SDKs or with C/C++ called through the JNI.
The system was implemented as a proof of concept on a Raspberry Pi.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This company is no longer in business.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;other-experiences&#34;&gt;Other Experiences&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;personal-projects&#34;&gt;Personal Projects&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See the &lt;a href=&#34;http://lynnjm7.github.io/#projects&#34;&gt;my projects&lt;/a&gt; for a listing of projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;founder-organizer-las-vegas-go-meetup-july-2015-present&#34;&gt;Founder &amp;amp; Organizer, Las Vegas Go Meetup, &lt;em&gt;July 2015 ~ Present&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organized presentations and meetings for programmers to discuss the Go programming language
and to create an environment to foster the growth and development of the Las Vegas Golang
community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;founder-organizer-las-vegas-siggraph-meetup-september-2015-present&#34;&gt;Founder &amp;amp; Organizer, Las Vegas SIGGRAPH Meetup, &lt;em&gt;September 2015 ~ Present&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organized presentations and meetings for artists, engineers, and researchers to
discuss computer graphics and interactive techniques.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;professional-memberships&#34;&gt;Professional Memberships&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ACM and SIGGRAPH, since 2011&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IEEE and IEEE/CS, since 2011&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SIAM, since 2012&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IGDA, since 2016&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A new site and a new start.</title>
      <link>http://lynnjm7.github.io/post/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2016 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lynnjm7.github.io/post/intro/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fresh-start&#34;&gt;Fresh start&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the inaugural post on this new blog and site! Thanks for reading it,
hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to find the time to keep this site updated with my
projects and qualifications. My intention is for this site to be the landing
page for my portfolio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for checking in here and stay tuned for more posts!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aptcast</title>
      <link>http://lynnjm7.github.io/project/aptcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lynnjm7.github.io/project/aptcast/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;origins&#34;&gt;Origins&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aptcast started as an Internet Listing Service (ILS) for apartment communities.
The primary goal of the project was to create a native iOS and Android app that
could be white labelled for individual property management companies for their
portfolios.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-ils&#34;&gt;The ILS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The iOS version Aptcast was officially released at NAA 2015 in Las Vegas, NV. It
was implemented in Swift with Objective-C and C for certain components. The use
of C for this project was to improve performance and reduce memory consumption
on mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key feature of the app was generating a heat-map overlay for the Google Maps
iOS SDK that displayed the price differences between various zip codes. This
required writing a custom GeoJSON parser that could generate the appropriate
polygons that would then be applied to the map. To reduce memory requirements
and improve rendering performance, several vertex processing algorithms were used
to decrease the number of vertices required to render the polygon on the map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;residents&#34;&gt;Residents&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After receiving feedback from several of our customers, development of the Aptcast
ILS was discontinued in favor of pursuing a new line of Aptcast apps that were
geared towards residents of apartment communities. These new Aptcast Resident
apps were implemented with Ionic and Cordova and designed to be white labeled
for individual communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-role-in-aptcast&#34;&gt;My role in Aptcast&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My role in these projects varied. For the ILS version of Aptcast, I was the
principal engineer on implementing both the app and the REST APIs that it was
interacting with. The Aptcast REST APIs were implemented using Go, Python, and
Amazon Web Services infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the resident apps, I worked on the REST APIs and supervised the team of
developers and designers that were implementing the Ionic apps.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GenIgnore</title>
      <link>http://lynnjm7.github.io/project/genignore/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lynnjm7.github.io/project/genignore/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
