<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Josh Lynn</title>
    <link>http://lynnjm7.github.io/tags/android/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Josh Lynn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016 Josh Lynn</copyright>
    <atom:link href="/tags/android/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Aptcast</title>
      <link>http://lynnjm7.github.io/project/aptcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lynnjm7.github.io/project/aptcast/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;origins&#34;&gt;Origins&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aptcast started as an Internet Listing Service (ILS) for apartment communities.
The primary goal of the project was to create a native iOS and Android app that
could be white labelled for individual property management companies for their
portfolios.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-ils&#34;&gt;The ILS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The iOS version Aptcast was officially released at NAA 2015 in Las Vegas, NV. It
was implemented in Swift with Objective-C and C for certain components. The use
of C for this project was to improve performance and reduce memory consumption
on mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key feature of the app was generating a heat-map overlay for the Google Maps
iOS SDK that displayed the price differences between various zip codes. This
required writing a custom GeoJSON parser that could generate the appropriate
polygons that would then be applied to the map. To reduce memory requirements
and improve rendering performance, several vertex processing algorithms were used
to decrease the number of vertices required to render the polygon on the map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;residents&#34;&gt;Residents&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After receiving feedback from several of our customers, development of the Aptcast
ILS was discontinued in favor of pursuing a new line of Aptcast apps that were
geared towards residents of apartment communities. These new Aptcast Resident
apps were implemented with Ionic and Cordova and designed to be white labeled
for individual communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-role-in-aptcast&#34;&gt;My role in Aptcast&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My role in these projects varied. For the ILS version of Aptcast, I was the
principal engineer on implementing both the app and the REST APIs that it was
interacting with. The Aptcast REST APIs were implemented using Go, Python, and
Amazon Web Services infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the resident apps, I worked on the REST APIs and supervised the team of
developers and designers that were implementing the Ionic apps.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
