<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publication-rsses on Josh Lynn</title>
    <link>http://lynnjm7.github.io/publication/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publication-rsses on Josh Lynn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016 Josh Lynn</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 17:42:15 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>An Intro to Swift&#39;s Type System</title>
      <link>http://lynnjm7.github.io/publication/swift_types/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 17:42:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lynnjm7.github.io/publication/swift_types/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This talk was presented at the Las Vegas iOS Developers Meetup and presented an
introduction to the basics of the Swift type system and how to describe basics
data structures in the Swift programming language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This talk begins with a treatment of basic data oriented development and continues
on a tour through the basic structure of defining data in Swift. This talk was
prepared as part of a series of talks on helping new iOS Developers learn Swift
and programming.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Object Orientation in Go</title>
      <link>http://lynnjm7.github.io/publication/objects_in_go/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 17:34:27 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lynnjm7.github.io/publication/objects_in_go/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Object oriented programing poses a unique approach to problem solving that some
developers, when first learning Go, struggle to work through. This talk addresses
some of those issues and illustrates a simplified way of thinking about object
oriented programming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To view these slides, you will need to setup the go present tool. For more
information on using this tool, please see the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://godoc.org/golang.org/x/tools/present&#34;&gt;present tools docs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The information presented in these slides is in the &lt;code&gt;gooo.slide&lt;/code&gt; file in the
linked repository.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>http://lynnjm7.github.io/publication/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 13:07:45 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lynnjm7.github.io/publication/resume/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;education&#34;&gt;Education&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BS Computer Science, Math Minor. University of Nevada, Las Vegas, December 2012&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;skills&#34;&gt;Skills&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Programming Languages:&lt;/strong&gt; C, C++, C#, Java, Objective-C, Swift, Python, JavaScript, Go&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Graphics Libraries and Tools:&lt;/strong&gt; OpenGL, OpenGL ES, WebGL, GLSL, CUDA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Databases:&lt;/strong&gt; SQLite, MySQL, PostgreSQL, DynamoDB, MongoDB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Operating Systems:&lt;/strong&gt; macOS, Windows, Linux, iOS, Android&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Development Tools:&lt;/strong&gt; Git, Maven, Gradle, Make, Android Studio/IntelliJ, Xcode, Visual Studio, Vim&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Development Methodologies:&lt;/strong&gt; Scrum, Agile, TDD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;employment-history&#34;&gt;Employment History&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lead-software-engineer-apartments247-com-june-2015-present&#34;&gt;Lead Software Engineer, Apartments247.com, &lt;em&gt;June 2015 ~ Present&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the responsibilities discussed in the &lt;code&gt;Software Engineer&lt;/code&gt; position
below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managed a team of 8-12 engineers on various projects, including REST APIs,
iOS and Android apps, and internal tooling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supervised team of engineers and designers in creating a series of mobile apps
for residents of apartment communities. These apps were designed to be white
labeled for the branding of various communities. The apps were implemented
with Ionic and Apache Cordova.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Directly lead team in developing REST APIs on AWS infrastructure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;software-engineer-apartments247-com-december-2014-present&#34;&gt;Software Engineer, Apartments247.com, &lt;em&gt;December 2014 ~ Present&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lead engineer on constructing JSON REST APIs on a distributed, microservice
infrastructure on AWS. The services were built leveraging different AWS
services including, SQS, DynamoDB, Aurora, Lambda, EC2, S3, and API Gateway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Engineered and implemented an Internet Listing Service (ILS) for apartment
communities. The Aptcast ILS was implemented with Swift (with some use of
C and Objective-C for various components) and released for iPhone. Project
discontinued due to business decisions to focus on Resident apps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed and implemented microservice APIs in Java, Go, Node, and Python
that were used for the Aptcast apps. These became the foundation for new
product development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;software-development-engineer-contract-galavantier-february-2014-july-2014&#34;&gt;Software Development Engineer (Contract), Galavantier, &lt;em&gt;February 2014 ~ July 2014&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technical lead on &lt;em&gt;Marko&amp;rsquo;s Guest List&lt;/em&gt; iOS app, implemented in Objective-C. The
app consumed a JSON REST API.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintained and extended existing Drupal REST APIs with PHP and MySQL.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented a custom Customer Service pipeline to aid service representatives
in responding to leads generated from the iOS app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;software-engineer-contract-lambda-td-software-inc-june-2013-december-2013&#34;&gt;Software Engineer (Contract), Lambda TD Software, Inc., &lt;em&gt;June 2013 ~ December 2013&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented features and bug fixes on the  &lt;em&gt;LFE Five Home Automation Platform&lt;/em&gt;. The platform
consisted of a REST API implemented in Java with Spring and PostgreSQL. The goal of the project
was to create a system that would provide a common interface for users to interact
with multiple home automation protocols. The API used existing Java SDKs or
called C/C++ through the JNI for interacting with the protocols. The system was
implemented as a proof of concept on a Raspberry Pi.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;other-experiences&#34;&gt;Other Experiences&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;personal-projects&#34;&gt;Personal Projects&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;http://lynnjm7.github.io/#projects&#34;&gt;my projects&lt;/a&gt; for a listing of projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;founder-organizer-las-vegas-go-meetup-july-2015-present&#34;&gt;Founder &amp;amp; Organizer, Las Vegas Go Meetup, &lt;em&gt;July 2015 ~ Present&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organized presentations and meetings to discuss the Go programming language
to create an environment fostering the growth and development of the Las Vegas Golang
community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;founder-organizer-las-vegas-siggraph-meetup-september-2015-present&#34;&gt;Founder &amp;amp; Organizer, Las Vegas SIGGRAPH Meetup, &lt;em&gt;September 2015 ~ Present&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organized presentations and meetings for artists, engineers, and researchers to
discuss computer graphics and interactive techniques.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;professional-memberships&#34;&gt;Professional Memberships&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ACM and SIGGRAPH, since 2011&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IEEE and IEEE/CS, since 2011&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SIAM, since 2012&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IGDA, since 2016&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
